MIKE RIVERA

San Diego, CA 92126

Phone: 858.603.6731 | Email: mike@sddeveloper.io LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/msrivera/ GitHub: https://github.com/DevMike42 Portfolio: https://michaelsrivera.com/

SUMMARY

Highly organized individual with over 10 years of problem-solving experience in search of a new career path in the tech industry as a Full Stack Web Developer. I hope to obtain a position in which I can combine both the skills in front-end and back-end web development with my desire to improve and strong work ethic to assist a company in meeting and surpassing its goals for success!

SKILLS

Languages: HTML5 | CSS | JavaScript | SOL | JSX

Tools, Frameworks, & Libraries: React.js | Bootstrap | Materialize | Handlebars.js | Axios | JQuery | Node.js | MySQL

| MongoDB | Mongoose | Express.js | ES6 | Sass

Concepts: Responsive Design | MVC Pattern | C.R.U.D. | APIs | MERN Stack | Big O Notation

PROJECTS

MADPass

GitHub - https://github.com/DarrenVictoriano/MAD-Protection Deployed - https://madpass.herokuapp.com/

- MADPass is the basic implementation of a password manager allowing a user to only remember one login and password for the app itself. All other login credentials are encrypted and stored in the user's Vault to be accessed quickly and easily.
- Core responsibilities included utilizing React to create multiple modals for capturing user input, using Axios for making client side HTTP requests, and general bug fixing.
- MongoDB | Express.js | React.js | Node.js | bcrypt | crypto.js | JWT

Reflect

Github - https://github.com/IrvinGutierrez6117/Project_2 Deployed - https://mindblog.herokuapp.com/

- A journaling application that allows a user to record their daily thoughts while recording their mood and time of day to be used in generating graphs showing the data supplied.
- Core responsibilities included working with Sequelize and MySQL to construct the database, create code for searching and retrieving data, and general bug fixing.
- HTML | CSS | JQuery | Node.js | Express.js | MySQL | Sequelize

EXPERIENCE

Teaching Assistant / Full Stack Development Bootcamp Course

Trilogy Education Services / University of Utah

2019 – Present Remote

- Admin duties Assignment/Project grading, managing course content updates on class repository, time tracking lectures to ensure we are on pace with the lesson plans, and taking role.
- Assisting students with in class activities and providing students with resources and guidance in order to help them learn to search for solutions to unknown problems and road blocks.

Service Department Manager / Technician

2000 - 2019

Trek Bicycle Superstore / Sport Chalet

San Diego, CA

Monitored and ensured all repairs were completed correctly and efficiently through detailed communication, planning, and skills training between myself and my staff.

EDUCATION

Bootcamp Certificate: University of California San Diego | San Diego, CA | 2019

A 24-week intensive program focused on gaining technical programming skills in HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, JQuery, Bootstrap, Firebase, Node Js, MySQL, MongoDB, Express, Handelbars.js & ReactJS.